<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Muizzkolapo</title>
    <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Muizzkolapo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Knowledge Graphs</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/knowledge_graphs/knowledge_graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/knowledge_graphs/knowledge_graphs/</guid>
      <description>Understanding how to work with knowledge graphs can give data scientists the ability to not just extract interrelated facts and assumptions from massive collections of data, but can also help in understanding how to form contextual connections and understanding from data via linking and semantic metadata which helps provide a unified approach to data analytics and intelligence. This article is an introduction to knowledge graphs, important concepts and their applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Augmentation for Cover Song Identification Systems Using Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/gan_music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/gan_music/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN) have seen great improvement in modelling synthetic data with results unparalleled in the field of deep learning. This research explores data augmentation for cover song identification by extending state-of-the-art GAN frameworks used in image processing to cover song identification. Research in this domain is still in the early phases, this work explores the implementation of a GAN model capable of generating new features for cover song identification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Learning University Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/learning_anallytics/analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/learning_anallytics/analysis/</guid>
      <description>The code above is to help format the notebook and make the outputs appear inline and within the document.
1.0 Data Preprocessing This is to load all the modules to be used in this analysis. The os module provides a way to interact with the Os of the machine, the glob module is used to retrieve the path names needed. Pandas,Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib.pyplot and Folium are modules used to interact with the dataset and plot visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact and Benefits of Car-Free Day on the Rhondda Cynon Taf Borough Using Statistical Evidence</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/pullution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/pullution/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The high impact of road transport on the environment calls for both scientific and social policies to control carbon and greenhouse gas emissions. The goal of this research is to study cars and taxis as a top contributor to CO2 emissions and reiterate the importance of putting policies in place to reduce car use. The CO, CO2 and greenhouse gas emissions were assessed in relation to local, national and International emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/twitter_airline_data_mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/twitter_airline_data_mining/</guid>
      <description>title: &amp;ldquo;Twitter data mining of airline related tweets&amp;rdquo; date: 2023-03-04T09:13:17Z draft: false
ReadMe
(1) For optimum performance of the code below ensure the following packages and libraries are installed and loaded to your Workspace.
tidytext stringr tidytext textdata stats reshape2 modeltools topicmodels tm widyr anytime rtweet leaflet lubridate lutz glue scales twitteR wordcloud igraph ggraph Ensure you run the code from Top to bottom as the content of the variable might change depending on the line of code been worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
