<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Muizzkolapo</title>
    <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Muizzkolapo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Knowledge Graphs</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/knowledge_graphs/knowledge_graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/knowledge_graphs/knowledge_graphs/</guid>
      <description>Understanding how to work with knowledge graphs can give data scientists the ability to not just extract interrelated facts and assumptions from massive collections of data, but can also help in understanding how to form contextual connections and understanding from data via linking and semantic metadata which helps provide a unified approach to data analytics and intelligence. This article is an introduction to knowledge graphs, important concepts and their applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply the gradient descent algorithm to custom functions</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/gradient_descent_custom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/gradient_descent_custom/</guid>
      <description>Applying the gradient descent algorithm to find the minimum of the following function of four variables
function
Introduction Gradient is an algorithm used to find the parameters that minimizes a function. We will be using the function above to implement gradient descent. To implement a gradient descent algorithm there are some important ingredients to be used which includes;
The function The partial derivative of all the function The gradient descent algorithm finds the best path to descend to the minimum points in a function by finding the slope of the tangent of the function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Augmentation for Cover Song Identification Systems Using Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/gan_music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/gan_music/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN) have seen great improvement in modelling synthetic data with results unparalleled in the field of deep learning. This research explores data augmentation for cover song identification by extending state-of-the-art GAN frameworks used in image processing to cover song identification. Research in this domain is still in the early phases, this work explores the implementation of a GAN model capable of generating new features for cover song identification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic Regression Modelling, Principal Component Analysis and Cluster Analysis Of Breast Cancer Dataset</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/breast_cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/breast_cancer/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Understanding how to work with breast cancer data to aid the early detection of breast cancer in women is very important to the health and wellbeing of women around the world. This study explores various statistical methods and techniques to analyze breast cancer related dataset, to discover if common statistical methods can be used to analyze these datasets. The impact of breast cancer on the well being of women provokes the need for both accurate and interpretable results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Learning University Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/learning_anallytics/analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/learning_anallytics/analysis/</guid>
      <description>The code above is to help format the notebook and make the outputs appear inline and within the document.
1.0 Data Preprocessing This is to load all the modules to be used in this analysis. The os module provides a way to interact with the Os of the machine, the glob module is used to retrieve the path names needed. Pandas,Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib.pyplot and Folium are modules used to interact with the dataset and plot visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact and Benefits of Car-Free Day on the Rhondda Cynon Taf Borough Using Statistical Evidence</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/pullution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/pullution/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The high impact of road transport on the environment calls for both scientific and social policies to control carbon and greenhouse gas emissions. The goal of this research is to study cars and taxis as a top contributor to CO2 emissions and reiterate the importance of putting policies in place to reduce car use. The CO, CO2 and greenhouse gas emissions were assessed in relation to local, national and International emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter data mining of airline related tweets</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/twitter_airline_data_mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/twitter_airline_data_mining/</guid>
      <description>Loading all packages needed using the package manager Package manager is a package that helps installs and load r packages when needed without having to call each package individually using the library function.
#loading package manager require(pacman) ## Loading required package: pacman #using p_load function to load all packages used pacman::p_load(tidyverse,tidytext,stringr,tidytext,textdata,stats, reshape2,modeltools,topicmodels,tm,widyr,anytime,rtweet, leaflet,lubridate,lutz,glue,scales,twitteR,wordcloud,igraph,ggraph) Problem statement Four tasks were performed on the airline tweet dataset provided including Text mining, Sentiment Analysis, Topic Model and Additional Exploratory Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Weather Time series analysis</title>
      <link>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/weather_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 09:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://muizzkolapo.github.io/blog/docs/weather_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Forecasting temperature by the use of advance statistical tools is very important in understanding and dealing with the effects of rising or decreasing temperatures. This study uses Time series analysis and predictions, a statistical methods to analyze and forecast temperatures, by using the average max, min and mean temperature for each month of different regions in the United Kingdom measured by the Met Office. The increase in concerns about the effects of rising or decreasing temperature on humans, animals, the climate, oceans, and seasonal patterns provokes the need for accurate models for forecasting the temperatures of the different regions across the globe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
